Nikhil Sawant

 $8080280902 \mid sawant.nikhilsawant.nikhil407@gmail.com \mid \underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikhil-sawant.nikhilsawant.nikhilsawant.nikhil407@gmail.com \mid \underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikhil-sawant.nikhilsawant.nikhilsawant.nikhil407@gmail.com \mid \underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikhil-sawant.nikhilsawant.nikhilsawant.nikhil407@gmail.com \mid \underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikhil-sawant.nikhilsawant.nikhi$

Profile

Skilled Digital Marketing Manager experienced in elevating business media and communications strategies. Adept at interpreting client requirements and devising campaigns to exceed profit, reach and growth targets. Proactive in forecasting and problem solving for smooth project delivery.

Experience

DIGITAL MEDIA PLANNER | GROUPM | JUNE 2022 - PRESENT

- · Devised bespoke media and communications plans to meet client growth goals.
- · Developed high-performing campaigns to boost engagement across Instagram, Facebook and LinkedIn.
- Built trusting partnerships with clients, maintaining long-term loyalty and increasing campaign spending.
- · Collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop and distribute media packages.
- · Forecasted delivery plans to meet timeframe and budget targets.
- · Responded quickly to technical issues for minimized project disruption.
- · Improved revenue generation by evolving campaign.
- possibilities with stakeholders and development teams.

DIGITAL ACCOUNT MANAGER | REALATTE VENTURES | JANUARY 2020 - JUNE 2022

- · Conducted throughout research into client's brand to determine most effective website keywords.
- · Helped teams reach ambitious sales objectives with multi- channel marketing campaigns.
- · Wrote copy for advertisements, email communications and media used in advertising.
- · Advised business clients on best mix of products for maximum sales and consumer engagement.
- · Selected distribution channels best suited to bespoke advertising objectives.
- · Used data to build strategies for targeting specific markets and consumer demographics.
- · Devised and executed innovative creative copy, maximizing brand engagement and reach.
- · Managed third-party platforms to deliver wide-reaching digital marketing campaigns.
- Took ownership of new client acquisition via digital marketing channels, devising strategies and managing marketing plan delivery.
- · Liaised with clients to discuss marketing strategy and campaign performance.

DIGITAL MARKETING EXECUTIVE | THREETEEN | JUNE 2017 - AUGUST 2018

- · Monitored campaigns to enforce adherence with agreed timeframes, budgets and requirements.
- Analyzed consumer behaviors to develop targeted engagement strategies for increased brand awareness.
- · Planned and implemented integrated search, display and video campaigns on platforms.
- Used Facebook, Instagram and YouTube to promote products and events.

DIGITAL MARKETING INTERN | WIREFLY DIGITAL | DECEMBER 2016 - MAY 2017

- Develop comprehensive paid media plans and recommendations for integrated digital marketing programs.
- Engage in daily monitoring and optimization of campaigns.
- · Provide daily, weekly, and monthly reporting and analysis.
- Ensure marketing optimization best practices are incorporated across the enterprise.

Education

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN HOSPITALITY MANAGEMENT | JUNE 2015 | RIZVI HMCT, MUMBAI

ADVANCED DIGITAL MARKETING CERTIFICATION | NOVEMBER 2016 | THE BRAND SALON, MUMBAI

Skills & Abilities

- · Market research expertise.
- · Campaign development experience.
- · Pay per click.
- · Media buying & planning.
- · Project Management.

- · Google AdWords Growth strategies.
- · Teamwork skills.
- · Promotions planning skills.
- · Time management.
- · Leadership skills.

Activities and Interests

Solo travelling, Powerlifting, Online gaming.